Franck mss., 1952-1966 LMC 2539
Lilly Library
Franck mss.
1952-1966
Lilly Library
Masefield, John, 1878-1967
LMC 2539
1 Box 1 standard
The Franck mss. consists of letters, 1952-1966, from John Masefield to researcher Nicolette Franck.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
The Franck mss., 1952-1966 contains letters from English writer John Masefield (1878-1967) to his employed researcher Nicolette Franck. Born in Ledbury, Masefield attended King's School in Warwcik for a brief period, before turning to a life at sea on board the HMS Conway. He went on many similar sea voyages, though he eventually became a factory worker. During World War I, excused from military service, he worked at a British hospital, briefly as an orderly. He also took to reading modern and classical literature, providing himself with his own education. The latter lead to collections of poems as well as prose novels throughout the early twentieth century. He is particularly known for his children's novels The Midnight Folk (1927) and The Box of Delights (1935). Between 1930 and 1967, Masefield also became Poet Laureate.
Scope and Content Note
The Franck mss. consists of letters and cards, 1952-1966, from John Masefield to researcher Nicolette Franck. The letters include research questions Masefield wants Franck to investigate, as well as Masefield's own reflections, experiences, and research observations.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 2006
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Franck, Nicolette; Masefield, John, 1878-1967
- Correspondence, John Masefield to Nicolette Franck (Box 1)
  - Handwritten Letter, Feb. 8, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten Letter, Feb. 27, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten Letter, May 4, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten Letter, May 6, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten Letter, May 12, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten Letter, July 4, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten Letter, July 8, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Handwritten Letter, July 10, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Handwritten Letter, July 22, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Handwritten Letter, Aug. 5, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Handwritten Letter, Aug. 14, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Typed Signed Letter, Aug. 21, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Handwritten Letter, Aug. 28, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Handwritten Letter, Sept. 3, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Handwritten Letter, Sept. 14, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Handwritten Letter, Oct. 14, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Handwritten Letter, Oct. 18, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Handwritten Letter, Oct. 29, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Book Token, May 9, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Signed Card, Dec. 25, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Handwritten Letter, Mar. 31, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Signed Card, Dec. 25, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Signed Card, Dec. 12, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Handwritten Letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Signed Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)